Kevin has 23 distinct personalities. The 24th is about to be unleashed.
Split is a horror, thriller film directed by M. Night Shyamalan.
Though Kevin has evidenced 23 personalities to his trusted psychiatrist, Dr.
Fletcher, there remains one still submerged who is set to
materialize and dominate all the others.
Compelled to abduct three teenage girls led by the willful, observant Casey, Kevin reaches a war for survival among all of
those contained within him — as well as everyone around him — as the walls between his compartments shatter apart.
Casey Cooke, played by Anya Taylor-Joy.
Dennis / Patricia / Hedwig / The Beast / Kevin Wendell Crumb /
Barry / Orwell / Jade, played by James McAvoy.
Claire Benoit, played by Haley Lu Richardson.
Marcia, played by Jessica Sula.
Dr. Karen Fletcher, played by Betty Buckley.
Five-Year-Old Casey, played by Izzie Coffey.
Split is a 2017 American psychological thriller film
written, directed and produced by M.
Night Shyamalan, and starring James McAvoy, Anya Taylor-Joy, and Betty Buckley.
It is the second installment in the Unbreakable trilogy and
a "stealth sequel" to Unbreakable (2000).
The film follows a man with dissociative identity disorder who kidnaps and
imprisons three teenage girls in an isolated underground facility.
Principal photography began on November 11, 2015, in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
The film premiered at Fantastic Fest on September 26, 2016, and was
released in the United States on January 20, 2017.
Unlike its predecessor, the film was distributed by Universal Pictures
instead of Touchstone Pictures, which went defunct in 2016.
It received generally positive reviews; critics highly praised McAvoy's performance, and welcomed Shyamalan's
direction, although some mental health advocates criticized the film for its stigmatization of mental illness.
Split was a commercial success, grossing $278 million worldwide on a budget of $9 million, becoming
Blumhouse Productions' highest-grossing film until 2023 when Five Nights at Freddy's overtook it.
The 2019 film Glass, which combined the casts and characters
of both previous films, concluded the trilogy.
The film explores themes of child abuse, philadelphia,
pennsylvania, kidnapping, gore, sequel.
The tone is intense and dark and mind_bending.